Guide to the Collection of Bookplates by William Edgar Fisher
Yale University Arts Library
Collection of Bookplates by William Edgar Fisher
1898-1961
1900-1947
BKP 96
Yale University Arts Library
0.83
(2 boxes)
This collection contains bookplates by William Edgar Fisher. Many of these bookplates, which were designed for both individual and institutional patrons, are prints signed and numbered by the artist; many are hand-colored as well. The collection also includes some correspondence by Fisher as well as letters exchanged by later collectors of his work.
Fisher, William Edgar, 1872-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Yale Bookplate Collection was formerly housed in Sterling Memorial Library. The collection was incorporated into the Arts of the Book Collection in 1984 and then moved to the Seeley G. Mudd Library in 1990. In 2011, it was transferred to the Robert B. Haas Family Arts Library.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
William Edgar Fisher (1872-1956) was born in Wellsville, NY. He studied at Cornell and the Art Institute of Chicago, focusing on architecture and particularly on draughtsmanship. He operated a studio in Fargo, ND, and designed nearly 200 ex-libris between 1898 and 1947. He was a member of the American Society of Bookplate Collectors & Designers and published five portfolios of bookplates.
References:
Bowdoin, W. G. "American Designers of Book-Plates: Wm. Edgar Fisher." In Book-Plates of To-Day, edited by Wilbur Macey Stone, 3-8. New York: Tonnelé & Company, 1902.
"Fisher, William Edgar." In volume I of Who Was Who in American Art, 1564-1975: 400 Years of Artists in America, edited by Peter Hastings Falk. Madison, CT: Sound View Press, 1999.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains bookplates by William Edgar Fisher. These are arranged chronologically according to a checklist published in The Second Year Book of the American Bookplate Society (1920). Many of these bookplates, which were designed for both individual and institutional patrons, are prints signed and numbered by the artist; many are hand-colored as well. The collection also includes some correspondence by Fisher as well as letters exchanged by later collectors of his work.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: I. Numbered Bookplates. II. Correspondence and Ephemera.
Bookplates -- Specimens.; Bookplates; Fisher, William Edgar, 1872-; Andrews, Irene Dwen, 1892-; Lowenhaupt, Warren Hiram, 1891-1967
- Numbered Bookplates, Series I
  - #3: Winifred Knight, 1898; 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - #4: Stanley Shepard, 1899; 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - #7: Silvanus Macy, Jr., 1899; 2 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - #8: Wm. Edgar Fisher, 1899; 2 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #9: Edna B. Stockhouse, 1899; 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - #15: Lula Thomas Wear, 1900; 2 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - #17: Elizabeth Langdon, 1900; 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - #19 & #19A: John Charles Gage, 1900; 3 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - #21: Samuel H. Hudson, 1900; 2 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #22: John Eliot Richards, 1900; 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - #28: Sara Grace Ball, 1900; 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - #29: Maie Bruce Douglas, 1900; 1 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - #31: Peyton C. Crenshaw, 1900; 4 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - #34: Mary N. Lewis, 1900; 3 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - #38: From the Library of the Studio Club, 1901; 2 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - #39: William Chauncey Langdon, 1901; 2 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - #44: Geo. H. Phelps, 1901; 1 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - #54: Adeline Cameron, 1901; 2 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - #55: TFF [T. Frank Fisher], 1901; 1 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - #60: William Edmund Ramsay, 1902; 3 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - #61: David S. Calhoun, 1902; 2 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - #62: Walter Williams Wait, 1902; 1 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - #65: Elizabeth Fitch Crane, 1902; 10 items (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - #71: Norman Day Otis, 1902; 4 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - #72: Harry Bradley, 1902; 4 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - #76: Florence O'Neill, 1903; 5 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - #77: Peter Bentz Smith, 1903; 3 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - #80: Eugene J. de Lendreçie, 1903; 4 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - #81: Snap Dragon Library | The Lady Mary from S. D., 1903; 3 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - #82: William Edgar Fisher, 1903; 4 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - #83: Robert Steele Lewis, 1903; 4 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - #84: James Orton Shepard, 1903; 5 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - #86: Helen Camp Curtis, 1903; 3 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - #88A: James S. Goldsmith, 1903; 5 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - #92: Louis J. Goldsmith, 1904; 5 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - #93: Justine Mann, 1904; 8 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - #94 & #94A: Luella May Compton, 1904; 9 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - #99: Horace Edsell Peck, 1904; 1 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - #100: Willet Ward, 1904; 5 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - #103: Kemper Hall, 1905; 1 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - #105: Wheaton Hale Brewer, 1905; 3 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - #107: Samuel Herbert McVitty, 1905; 6 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - #108: Anna Cora Stone, 1905; 7 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - #110: Olive Thorne Miller, 1905; 5 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - #111: Nannie Lamberton Wilbur, 1906; 6 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - #115: S. LeC. F., 1906; 6 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - #117: Arnold Broyles & Frances Divine Broyles, 1906; 4 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - #119: William Winters Knight & Edna Ford Knight, 1906; 3 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - #120: Fannie H. Knox, Marjorie Reltving, 1906; 7 items (2 Knox; 5 Reltving) (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - #122: The Wadsworth Library | Geneseo, NY, 1907; 5 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - #123: Cameron Mann, 1907; 3 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - #124: Eli L. Sanger, 1907; 5 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - #125: William Augustus Brewer, 1907; 8 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - #126: Alice B. McCutcheon, 1907; 2 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - #127: George Xavier McLanahan & Caroline Duer McLanahan, 1908; 5 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - #129: Theodora N. McCutcheon, 1908; 3 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - #130: Samuel Bradford Knight & Della Hood Knight, 1908; 4 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - #131: Gilbert Stuart McClintock, 1909; 3 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - #132: Nannie Huttig & Holmes Huttig, 1909; 3 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - #134: The Library of Bowdoin College | Gift of Class of 1882, 1909; 4 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - #135: William McLauchlan, 1909; 5 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - #137: Caswell Wheeler Stoddard, 1911; 2 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - #138: Bowdoin College Library, 1912; 1 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - #139: A. R. M. S. [Alice Rose Morton Simmons], 1913; 2 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - #141: Harry Lockwood Ransom & Mildred Forsythe Ransom, 1913; 2 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - #142: St. John's University Shanghai Low Library, 1913; 1 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - #145: Samuel W. Bowne, 1913; 2 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - #147: Stowell LeCain Fisher, 1914; 2 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - #148: William Edgar Fisher, 1914; 3 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - #149: Helen Duke, 1915; 4 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - #152: St. Katharine's School | Davenport, Iowa, 1917; 1 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - #156: Justine, 1920; 3 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - #159: Eleanor Ter Bush, 1920; 2 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - #160: Arthur Newton Pack, 1921; 2 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - #162: Mary H. Robinson, 1922; 2 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - #163: The Library of the University of Rochester, 1922; 2 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - #165: Ada L. Comstock, 1924; 5 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - #166: Herbert Godfrey Edwards, 1924; 3 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - #168: Edward G. Miner, 1926; 4 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - #169: Edward G. Miner Fund | The University of Rochester Library, 1926; 5 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - #170: Vera H. Hoff, 1926; 1 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - #172: Leod D. Becker, 1927; 3 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - #173: Daniel Magee Beach, Jr., 1927; 4 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - #174: Library of Princeton University | In Memory of Charles Richard Williams, 1928; 5 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - #175: The Bishop's Library South Florida | Gift of Cameron Mann, 1929; 5 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - #178: Florence MacLeod, 1930; 3 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - #180: The University of Rochester Library | From the Raymond N. Ball Fund, 1931; 6 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - #181: Herbert Hollands & Bertha C. Hollands, 1931; 5 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - #183: Betty Pellet, 1932; 5 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - #184: Maxwell E. Lapham, 1933; 4 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - #186: Logan Clendening, 1934; 3 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - #187: Smith College Library | Gift of the Class of 1898, 1939; 2 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - #188: The University of Rochester Library | In Memory of Donald Bean Gilchrist | Librarian 1919-1939, 1940; 5 (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - #190: Lewis Henry Thornton, II, 1941; 1 (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - #191: Lewis Henry Thornton, 1942; 3 (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - #192: Rosalie Alice Norman, 1943; 2 (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - #193: Corwin Black, 1944; 2 (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - #194: Library of the University of Virginia | In Memory of Clinton McClarty Harbison, A.B. '42 and John Henry Neff, A.B. '42, 1945; 2 (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - #195: James Thornton & Sarah Hawkes Thornton, 1946; 2 (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - #196: University of Virginia Alderman Library | The International Studies Collection, 1946; 2 (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - #197: Julius H. Fisher & Miriam T. Fisher, 1947; 2 (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - #198: V. P. T. [Virginia Pierson Thornton], 1947; 4 (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - #199: Jane Hawkes Thornton, 1947; 3 (Box 2, Folder 103)
- Correspondence and Ephemera, Series II
  - Correspondence and Ephemera, 1906-1961; 13 (Box 2, Folder 104)